#### Contact

(310) 658-2303 (Mobile) azmiamir@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amirazmi-96079a1b (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Troubleshooting
Team Leadership
Project Planning

#### Languages

French English Arabic

# Certifications CompTIA A+

## **Amir Azmi**

IT Support Specialist at PC Work Computers

Torrance, California

## Summary

I have more than 10 years of experience in small and big office Windows and Apple desktop support, printer support and networking.

Logical reasoning, creative problem-solving skills, and efficient time management. with the capacity to work independently as well as in a team-driven environment.

## Experience

PC Work Computers
IT Support Specialist
July 2017 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

- Managing help desk support and resolve problems to ensure end-user satisfaction.
- Walk end-users through a variety of problem-solving processes.
- Providing necessary training to computer users.
- Assessing hardware and software usage, network and device connectivity, etc.
- Managing VoIP phone systems, including deploying and supporting phones and extensions.
- Resolving technical problems with Local Area Networks (LAN), phone systems, virtual environments.
- Acting as a point of contact to set up PCs and deployment for new employees using standard hardware, images, and software.
- Modifying configurations, utilities, software default settings, etc. for the local workstation.
- Building and install new workstations, peripheral equipment, software, and migrate data as part of the upgrade process.
- Ensuring each workstation has the necessary equipment needed and any additional specialized equipment to support productivity.
- Maintaining an inventory of supplies and spare parts, OEM licensing management.

- Configuring and managing user accounts on Active Directory.
- Setting up smart conference rooms for meetings, ensuring internet connectivity, and mirroring laptop to the TV for presentations.
- Securing building access controls and observing the uptime of the CCTV system.

DSG Dynamic Solution Group Information Technology Specialist December 2014 - April 2017 (2 years 5 months)

Cairo Governorate, Egypt

- IT-related work such as provisioning and maintaining internal systems, as well as work on building tools for the automation of routine tasks.
- Administered mobile device management systems.
- Administered provisioning of new internal hardware and user setup.
- Implemented and maintained an IT asset management system.
- Implemented and monitored security measures for the protection of computer systems, networks, and information.
- Educated users success team on routine problems, to allow them to resolve things directly.
- · Assisted users with IT-related issues on-site or remotely.

#### United Nations OCHA

**ICT** Associate

March 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 8 months)

Cairo Governorate, Egypt

- Administrated under VMware server (ISA firewall server, Domain server, Data server, WEB servers, FTP server).
- Administrated Lotus Note and Black-Berry service server.
- Administrated the Avaya VOIP server.
- Designed and established a backup strategy for all virtual servers and data.
- Implemented and managed PC setup and deployment for new employees using standard hardware, images, and software.
- Responsible for handling and purchasing IT types of equipment.
- Managed ICT inventory in coordination with the administration unit.
- Provide technical support for specific Satellite internet VSAT, GPS, Thuraya phones.

#### Vodafone

Account Advisor

June 2009 - March 2012 (2 years 10 months)

Giza Governorate, Egypt

Account advisor-Team leader:

- Served UK customers in England.
- · Handled customer billing issues.
- Handled customer's smartphone and Black-Berry technical issues.
- Provided support and improvement plan for new employees in my team.

#### **ELNG**

IT Support Specialist

2008 - 2009 (1 year)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

Responsible for maintaining and support the following items for entire LNG staff in IDKU site:

- Troubleshot entire LNG user's software, hardware, and IP phone set conflicts and problems.
- Supported the Windows operating system, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Exchange, Active Directory, PDA interfaces, etc.
- Troubleshot MFP printers, copiers, digital sender and faxes problems.
- · Maintain and monitor the network.
- Configure and manage ELNG users' connectivity on Cisco IP telephone.
- Participate in the server's room transfer project.
- Part of the team responsible for implementing the wireless access points plan.

#### X-Lab Group

IT Support Senior Eng. network administrator

August 2006 - February 2008 (1 year 7 months)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Support Senior Eng. network admin of the Technical Department.

Handling all main project & technical team projects have done:

- The Sharm el-Sheikh International Arbitration Center (SHIAC)
- · network infra cabled and wireless.
- Internet leased line connection with the server firewall.
- · lp-sec webcam.
- Audio and video conference system.
- Smartboard system.
- Kabo JIL factory installing and manager database for 46 fingerprint device.

• IT Support for Lycee Francais Alexandria school (part of the French consul)

Maintenance contract.

#### PC LINK

IT Site Maintenance Eng.

January 2005 - August 2006 (1 year 8 months)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Site Maintenance Eng. for Alexandria Carbon Black Co.

Handling more than 150 PC's, Printers, Copier (hardware & software)

Troubleshooting, maintenance, and networking.

#### **New PC Planet**

IT Support

March 1997 - December 2001 (4 years 10 months)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Supervisor in the Technical Support Department.

- · Very good experience in networking.
- · Computer assembly.
- Installation of Windows and other common software.
- Troubleshooting most hardware and software problems & hardware conflicts.
- Resolving driver installation problems.
- System admin for the Center for French Studies (CEA) network consisting of 30 PC's and internet leased line.

## Education

#### Special Studies Academy

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering, Quality control and quality assurance for mechanical products. · (1999 - 2003)

College St. Marc, Alexandria

High school degree, Collège Saint Marc · (1983 - 1999)